August 27th, Stellar Year 2148
All right. If we have to. Thanks.
Was that Kino's group?
Yeah.
They looked hard, but they said
they can't find Chise's Juggernaut.
Not even a little piece of it, huh?
Well, after that artillery blast...
Yeah.
I'm sure it's not bothering you,
but I'll say it anyway.
It's not your fault.
I thought they'd come after our base next,
but they haven't.
Today's attack had a secondary goal
of testing that new weapon.
We lost four to a "secondary goal," huh?
If it's completed,
we'll lose a lot more than four.
The Republic will fall.
That doesn't matter to us,
but I doubt the Major will agree.
What?
Nothing.
Either way, the new one's
still silent, for now.
You can tell?
I memorized its voice.
And I doubt the enemy commander
will let them use it.
I found him.
Your brother?!
He found me, too.
He'll come for me next.
It's good luck for me,
but bad for all of you.
What will you do?
Hang yourself tonight,
before you die tomorrow?
Not a chance in hell.
We'll follow you to the end, Reaper.
We're going to be wiped out.
This unit is an execution ground.
Special orders...
Target: The deepest part
of Legion-held territory.
Mission duration: Unlimited.
No support...
Immediate execution in the event of retreat?
The point of this place is
to make the soldiers fight until they die.
This is the last place we'll serve.
We'll all die here.
What's wrong, Lena?
August 28th, Stellar Year 2148
A final mission with a survival rate of 0%, huh?
I guess that sounds like this country.
Please, help me!
I need to do something!
"Do something"?
Do what, specifically?
Go on TV and give a speech?
Find somebody important and yell at them?
If that would change minds, this never
things wouldn't be like this in the first place.
Give it up. We can't fix this.
Nothing we do matters, so just—
Stop it!
Stop pretending to be a bad person
just to have an excuse to do nothing!
You're the one who needs to stop!
Stop...
I mean it.
There's nothing we can do!
We can't do a thing to save them!
Annette...
Our next-door neighbors were scientists
on my dad's research team.
Our families were close.
But that all changed when the war started.
They were Eighty-Six.
Two boys.
The older brother was way older,
but the younger was my age.
We went to the same school
and played a lot.
We were friends.
But the next thing I knew,
the Eighty-Six all stopped coming to school.
And my classmates were bullying me.
They said I was friends
with a filthy colored.
It hurt! There wasn't
anything I could do!
But he didn't know anything
about it and still wanted to play.
I turned him down,
and we got in a fight.
And I said it...
You filthy colored!
I was scared.
I was scared of myself
for being capable of saying that.
So...
When my dad was thinking about
taking them in, despite the danger,
I said I didn't want to.
I said he wasn't my friend.
I said I wouldn't put myself in danger for him.
I think my dad wanted my support.
But I gave him a way out.
They were sent to the camps
the next day.
All I could do was tell myself
I couldn't do anything.
That there was never a chance.
But you... You always...
Listen, Lena.
You may act like a saint,
but you're just as guilty as me.
What is this place?
The kids who lived next door,
and their mother, had a strange power.
They could tell what each other felt
without speaking.
My dad took an interest in that power.
This is where it began.
First, they'd put on
these little toy-like devices,
and try to guess what their mom
was thinking behind the curtain.
The experiments were like a game.
But when the military found out
that there was
a new kind of communication
that could replace wireless,
they ordered my dad to perfect it,
no matter what the cost.
And the result...
was the RAID device you're wearing.
How many Eighty-Six do you think
died to make it?
It shares words.
You can't use animals, right?
You don't mean—
That's right. Human experimentation.
Even though they said
the Eighty-Six aren't human.
Convenient, right?
All the test subjects were children.
Results first. Safety last.
They all died suffering.
My dad couldn't take it.
He committed suicide.
It wasn't an accident?
You think my dad of all people
would screw up the settings on a Para-RAID?
He always told me that he'd abandoned his friends
and caused so many deaths.
He deserved to suffer and die
more than anyone.
Which means I'm just as guilty
for abandoning my friend, right?
So I took over the research my dad did,
victims and all!
"Undertaker," was it?
We got the request to investigate
because of the dead Handlers, remember?
Yeah...
If I'd had them bring the Processor
that was the cause,
I might've been able to save him,
if nobody else.
But that's just hypocrisy.
I'm glad those shitheads in Transport refused.
See? Nothing we can do.
I can't save anyone.
But you're no different!
You're even worse!
You interfered and kept them alive,
and now they're being ordered to die!
If you'd just slacked off and let them die,
they wouldn't have gotten that order.
And now they will, thanks to you!
I hate you, Lena.
Never let me see you again.
I won't let them die.
I won't let anyone else die.
September 10th, Stellar Year 2148
What do you want?
Let me cancel the special recon orders
given to Spearhead!
I told you not to get too involved.
This is insane!
Must they keep marching into enemy territory
until they're dead, for no reason?
The Eighty-Six all need to die.
That's what's best for the country,
according to its government,
and indirectly, its people.
That's the will of the nation.
If what we've done to the Eighty-Six
gets out at the end of the war,
the Republic will become a pariah state
and remembered forever as oppressors.
And to keep that from happening...
And that's why you forbid them
from recovering or burying their dead?
When they're all dead,
they will cease to have existed.
And thus, the Republic
will have done nothing wrong.
A very small number know the exact truth.
But the vast majority who look the other way,
or just don't care, are supporters of this.
And our job as the army, Lena,
is to follow the people's wishes!
The Eighty-Six are part of the Republic as well!
The Republican ideals that Saint Magnolia
expounded should protect them, too!
If they aren't, how can this
be the will of the Republic?!
It's a country full of fools and villains,
who executed Saint Magnolia for the
sake of their own wealth and greed.
What can you expect of them?!
Humans were not ready
to have freedom and equality.
And I think we'll ever be.
You're just saying that
to justify your despair!
It's wrong to sit back
and let this happen!
You're free to speak of your hopes and ideals,
but you won't persuade anyone.
That's why you came to me, right?
Hope and despair are the same thing.
You want something, and you can't have it.
They're two names
for two sides of the same thing.
Captain Nouzen,
I have a set of special recon orders.
I've received them.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't do anything.
I'm sure.
There's no need
to obey these ridiculous orders.
Run away.
To where?
Everyone dies someday.
You can't blame someone just
because that day came a little early.
Why do you always just accept it?!
You're losing your future, your wishes,
even your life...
And you don't hate us?
How is that possible?!
Major, we're not going to die.
We're finally following the path
we wanted to follow,
to the place we wanted to go.
We can finally be free.
I would prefer you didn't disparage that.
Then... Then at least don't fight any more.
I have to.
We need to fight to go forward.
We've known it from the start.
To kill your brother, right?
Why did you have to realize that?
I can tell...
You're sad, but you still laugh coldly
when you talk about your brother.
Don't fight, please.
Even if he's part of the Legion,
you can't fight your brother.
My brother is a Shepherd.
I can't go anywhere without killing him.
Captain!
Major...
There is no need to monitor us anymore.
Does that mean—
I don't want you
to hear my brother's last words.
So please don't contact us again.
Go past the eastern border,
and you'll no longer hear the Legion's voices.
If anyone's left alive, help may come there.
When a Shepherd dies,
it throws the Legion into chaos for a while.
We can buy you that much time.
So...
Captain Nouzen...
Survive until then.
September 27th, Stellar Year 2148
Well?
Provisions, fuel, ammo,
and spare parts are all packed.
I also packed extra spares for the legs,
for a certain idiot commander.
Thank you.
You can do simple repairs yourself, right?
Yeah. I break them a lot.
Act a little ashamed, brat!
Don't fight like you usually do.
I can't promise.
It's the last time, so just lie and agree.
I'm sorry.
Jeez...
You really are...
I feel bad for Haruto.
If he'd lasted a little longer,
he could've gone for a fun hike.
Yeah.
Think the rain'll stop?
It'd be nice to have clear skies,
at least for the first day.
I know a trick! Kaie used to do it!
Hey, kids! Come here.
Now that it's the last time,
I realize I'm gonna miss the old guy's lectures.
You think?
Let's eat!
September 28th, Stellar Year 2148
We all gathered here on the first day, right?
You mean the day we were assigned here?
Yup.
Yeah, we all swore to each other again.
"No matter who calls us pigs,
we'll never let ourselves become them."
"Even if we're the last one,
we'll fight until the last day."
And all five of us survived.
Not bad.
The Major never did call back.
What, you miss her?
Not at all.
I guess it does kind of bug me, though.
After all the time we've spent together,
she could've said goodbye.
Yeah, like that.
We told her a million times to leave us alone,
and she finally got it, is all.
The rain stopped.
Clear skies!
The trick worked, huh?
It's a good omen!
Look, look!
They're all shiny!
I cleaned all your marks, too.
You're nice and clean, too.
How cool!
He's happy?
He was filthy.
I'm happy for you.
What's this?
Snacks.
Is this...
He treated us like kids until the end.
Nobody forgot anything, right?
Nope!
No.
Shin.
Let's go.
I wanted to protect you.
That was how it was supposed to be, but...
Shin.
Brother, are Mom and Dad not coming back?
Why?
I could barely keep myself together back then.
I can't hear Mom's voice.
Brother, why did Mom die?
It's your fault!
That's not true.
Mom went to fight because of you!
You killed her.
Stop it!
It's your fault.
That's not true.
It's all your fault.
It's not your fault.
That Mom and Dad died.
The fact that I'm about to die.
It's all your fault,
Shin!
I...
I couldn't handle the hate and rage
I felt at my own powerlessness,
and I took it out on you,
the person I was supposed to protect.
I couldn't protect you.
But...
Shin...
Now we'll be together forever.
I'm coming for you.
Without my fragile human body.
This time,
your brother will protect you forever.
So...
Come see me, Shin!
"Goodbye."